Colton Kaiser

Seattle, WA (Willing to relocate) | 480-229-1745 | kaiserc2@seattleu.edu | LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/coltonkaiser</u> Portfolio: <u>coltonkaiser.dev</u> | GitHub: <u>github.com/ckaiser258</u> | Blog: <u>medium.com/@coltonkaiser</u>

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Full-stack software engineer with five years of experience in strength and conditioning. My education and experience provide me with strong analytical skills, communication skills, and a systems-driven mindset which informs my coding. I am excited to combine my leadership skills with my software engineering expertise to contribute to an organization that values professionalism, collaboration, and offers a rich environment for constant growth and improvement.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

ReactJS, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, Ruby, SQL, OO Design, RESTful APIs, Postgres, HTML/CSS, Git Version Control HackerRank React Certified, HackerRank JavaScript Certified

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Performance Mapper - Github Frontend | Github Backend | Demo Video | Live Demo

An athletic performance monitoring tool that allows strength and conditioning coaches to monitor the performance and injury trends of their teams/athletes

- Used ReactJS, React Bootstrap, and Material UI for the frontend user experience
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side
- Created a Rails backend with BCrypt to allow users to securely store, access, and modify their information
- Used React ChartJS to display recorded subjective data for individual athletes as well as objective trends in performance and injuries throughout the user's teams

Movie Shelf - Github Frontend | Github Backend | Demo Video | Live Demo

An app that allows a user to add their favorite movies to a personal shelf and view information about each

- Developed an app that allows users to search for movies, view information and add, edit, and delete each one. Collaborated with a team of programmers
- Utilized the OMDB API to allow a user to search through thousands of movies and be provided information on each
- Created a Rails backend for the user to store their respective movies
- Used ReactJS along with React Bootstrap to create an efficient user experience
- Created POST, PATCH, and DELETE request for full CRUD functionality

VisionBoard - Github Frontend | Github Backend | Demo Video | Live Demo

A goal monitoring tool that allows users to keep track of and customize personal and professional goals

- Programmed an app that allows users to sign up, create boards, and add goals to their respective boards along with CRUD operations for each. Collaborated with a team of four programmers
- Used a Rails backend to store new users and boards/goals saved by the user
- Used vanilla Javascript to set up event handling and increase user interaction capabilities
- Styled and structured the app with HTML and CSS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Software Engineer Snowpool

Seattle, WA 08/2020 - Current

- Assisting a team from Veda Environmental in the development of a carpooling application aimed at making Washington's snow sport destinations more accessible and environmentally approachable for the residents of the local areas.
- Working with a team of software engineers, requiring effective git version control, communication, teamwork, meeting deadlines, and setting/adhering to clear expectations.
- Utilizing React, React Native, JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, and PostgreSQL to develop features.
- Working with UX/UI designers to implement mockups/wireframes to create an engaging user experience.

Software Engineering Apprentice

Flatiron School

Seattle, WA 04/2020 - 08/2020

- Developed skillsets in Ruby, Rails, Javascript, React/Redux, SQL, Computer Science fundamentals, HTML/CSS, data structure libraries for solving algorithms, and created multiple projects/full-stack applications.
- Learned full-stack software engineering via test-driven development, using git version control to collaborate on pair programming projects, and solo projects.

Vigor Ground Performance

Head of Sports Performance

Seattle, WA 07/2019-04/2020

- Was in a leadership position for a department dedicated to growing the business and revenue for a target population
- Created and lead athletic performance programs built through systematic progressions and regular testing
- Collaborated and built rapport with sport coaches and athletic trainers to achieve a common goal for each team/athlete, and use problem-solving along the way
- Gained public speaking and organizational skills by creating and leading seminars
- Provided leadership, education and management for groups of interns

Seattle Professional Rugby

Injured Players Coordinator

Seattle, WA 02/2019 - 06/2019

- Programmed, scheduled, and coached all long-term injured players for return to play
- Created return-to-play programs with a heavy emphasis on injury analysis and rehab procedures
- Learned data collection and utilization to monitor performance/workload and program accordingly

Seattle University

Graduate Assistant Strength and Conditioning Coach

Seattle, WA

06/2017 - 08/2019

- Utilized leadership and time-management skills to program and implemented strength, speed, and conditioning programs for over 120 athletes
- Maintained a systematic yet flexible approach to sports performance and injury prevention through the use of performance data collection and movement analysis
- Collaborated with sport coaches and athletic trainers to ensure an integrated system for athletic performance enhancement
- Created and fostered a team environment that is challenging, motivating and conducive to growth

Florida International University

Strength and Conditioning Intern

Miami, FL 06/2018 - 08/2018

- Assisted with the coaching & implementation of the summer strength, speed, conditioning, & injury prevention program for over 100 football athletes and six other teams
- Gained experience learning to program for a very large and diverse group of athletes
- Completed a full and comprehensive intern education curriculum covering all aspects of sports performance as well as career management
- Pushed through discomfort and adapted to a high-pressure environment

EDUCATION

Flatiron SchoolSeattle, WA
Full Stack Software Development, Software Engineering Immersive Program
04/2020 - 08/2020

. ,

Seattle, WA

Seattle UniversityM.A. in Sports Administration & Leadership (3.7 GPA)

Arizona State University

Phoenix, AZ 06/ 2016

06/2019

B.S. in Exercise Science